敵の戦術は極めて単純だ
The enemy's battle plan is incredibly simple.
Clear the vicinity with the shockwave
from the impact of the Landing Castles,
揚陸城の落下による衝撃波で一帯を掃討し
which both eliminates our forces and provides a beachhead.
こちらの戦力を排除すると同時に拠点を設営するつもりでいる
But we've spent the past fifteen years preparing for such an attack.
だがこちらは15年前からその作戦を想定済みである
We will concentrate all our forces
全ての戦力を結集し
and destroy the enemy before
.their ground troops can deploy.
敵地上部隊に先んじて包囲し殲滅する
Go.
以上だ
kimi ga miru yume wa
Your selfless dream
君が見る夢は　古いインクで紙に書いた祈りのよう
furui inku de kami ni kaita inori no you
is like a prayer written on paper with yellowing ink
chiisana sono te ga sugaru mono mo
Your fragile hands seek support,
小さなその手が　縋るものも　今はまだ何処にも無い
ima wa mada hitori mo nai
and yet have nothing at all to cling to
sore demo kimi no yuku michi wo
But even so, I want to guard
それでも君の行く道を
kirei na mono wa kirei na mama de
the path you walk
奇麗なものは奇麗なままで　守り続けたいと思うよ
mamoritsuzuketai to omou yo
in all my beauty
sora to mizu ga hoshi wo somete
I can see our skies and seas in the stars
空と水が星を染めて
awaku michi wo egaite chitte
before they fall to pave our faint road
淡く虹を描いて散って
mabushii yoru kimi ga utau
Light tears through the night and you sing
眩しい夜　君が歌う
koe wa doko made todoku no darou
How far will your voice travel?
声は何処まで届くのだろう
akogare no sumau aoi hoshi no hikari
This is the light of the blue planet I admire,
憧れの住まう蒼い星のひかり
tada bokura wa koi wo shite
the light that we love helplessly
ただ僕らは恋をして
tatta hitotsu no mirai no tame ni
We sacrifice all we have at our disposal
たったひとつの未来の為に
ima no subete kanadeteiru
for the only future we have left
今の全て奏でてみる
tobitatsu yo
Let us fly
飛び立つよ　まだ暗い空へ
mada kurai sora he
into the blackened sky
That...
あれが…
is a Martian Landing Castle.
火星　揚陸城
制圧せよ
Commence suppression.
くそったれ
Bastards!
Enemy missiles!
敵ミサイル
Intercept them!
迎撃しろ　RAM
Launch RAMs!
Wait.
いえ
Southern Cross cable,
Concerto One cable: link severed.
海底ケーブル　サザンクロス　コンチェルト1　切断
マイアミランディングステーション　沈黙
Contact with Miami Landing Station lost.
What about the comm satellites?
通信衛星を
The Landing Castles in orbit are attacking them!
軌道上の揚陸城から攻撃を受けています
Contact with United Earth HQ and regional offices lost.
連合本部　支部　共に通信途絶
アルファリーダーより各機
Alpha Leader to all planes.
Begin your attack!
これより攻撃に移る
なに…
What?
The squadron was annihilated?
航空部隊が…
One enemy encountered.
シルバー22
Silver 2-2?
ジャミングか
Are we being jammed?
先行するシルバー小隊が敵と接触した模様
Silver Platoon in the vanguard
seems to have made enemy contact.
全機展開　各個に攻撃せよ
All units, deploy.
Attack at will.
あいつか
That thing, huh?
隊長
Commander!
You foolish cavemen.
愚かなる原始人共　神の威光にひれ伏すがいい
Prostrate yourselves before God's authority.
恭順か　絶滅か
Swear allegiance, or be annihilated.
Your choice is one of the two.
貴様らの道は二つに一つ
Pathetic.
哀れよな…
一体何なんだ
What in the world?
Are those...
あれが…　火星カタフラクト
Martian Cataphracts?
There's no way that we can win.
勝てるわけがねえ
俺たちは　虫だ　虫けらと　同じ…
We're like insects to them.
Just insects...
造作も無い
What meek opposition.
Count Cruhteo.
クルーテオ卿
We must march on Shin-awara without delay.
今すぐ新芦原に進軍すべきです
If we plant our glorious flag on the site of Her Highness' tragic demise,
我らが姫の悲運の地に御旗を掲げば
the justness of our path will be evident to all.
ヴァースの大義は　より確固たる物となりましょう
Indeed. That was my intention.
うむ　元よりそのつもり
However, I must prioritize
securing the beachhead for now.
だがまずは　落着地制圧が急務
Then please entrust me, Trillram, with it.
ならばクルーテオ卿　ぜひこのトリルランにお任せを
I would treasure the chance to repay you for the kindness and hospitality you've always shown me.
長らく食客に甘んじた御恩を果たすに　絶好の機会
Very well, Trillram.
貴公に委ねよう　トリルラン
Capture this area's leader and learn what you can about Her Highness' death.
当地の責任者を拘束し　姫の死にまつわる仔細を明らかにするのだ
はっ
Yes, my lord.
緊急速報です
Emergency report.
Major cities around the world
先ほど　世界各地の主要都市に火星のヴァース帝国軍による
UNDER ATTACK FROM VERS IMPERIAL MILITARY
have come under attack from the Martian Vers empire.
軍事攻撃が行われましたが
Due to an unexplained loss of communication,
現在　原因不明の通信障害のため
各都市の詳細な被害について…
we cannot estimate...
定員には十分な余裕があります
We have enough room for everyone.
Please walk in an orderly fashion.
焦らずゆっくり　落ち着いて行動してください
To all residents of Shin-awara:
新芦原市の皆さん　避難勧告が発令されています
an evacuation advisory is in effect.
Please respond if you hear this message.
逃げ遅れている方はいらっしゃいませんか
Hey...
Hm?
How did we get press-ganged into this?
何で俺達まで駆り出されちゃってんの
仕方ないだろう　人手不足なんだから
Don't complain.
They're short on manpower.
And I couldn't say no to Inko.
韻子には逆らえないし
I don't mind helping the student council with normal stuff,
生徒会の手伝いならまだしもよ
but if this war turns really serious, we're sure to get conscripted.
このまま戦争が本格化してさ　俺たちもいつか徴兵されたりするわけ
No way.
まさか　予備役は高卒からだろう
Only high school graduates are put in reserve units.
But, you know,
ただまぁ　戦局が長引いて　兵隊不足にでもなったら
if this war drags out and the losses mount,
perhaps we will.
あるいはな…
Inko, family at ten o'clock.
韻子　10時の方向に家族連れ発見
Man...
まじかよ
Fuck the Martians.
ファック火星人
Huh?
I said I'm on standby, so I can't go with you.
だから　待機任務かかっちゃったから　お姉ちゃん動けないんだって
Didn't we agree we'd leave town in your car?
ユキ姉の車で避難するって話じゃなかったっけ
What?
え?　もしかしてなお君　まだ家にいるの
Don't tell me you're still at the house, Nao!
Why didn't you evacuate with the others?!
どうして皆と逃げなかったの
Oh, right. I guess I could have.
なるほど　そういう…
Adapt your plans to fit the situation!
判断は臨機応変
If you have to, trust your gut and make the call!
いざとなれば自分を信じて決断する
お姉ちゃんいつも言って聞かせてるでしょう
Aren't I always telling you that?
Penivia.
ベニビア
何?
What?
何でもないよ
Nothing.
I'll get a lift from one of the transports going around town.
巡回中の輸送車に拾ってもらう事にする
Be careful!
気を付けてね
You too.
ユキ姉こそ
Um...
あの…早く逃げないと
You should escape.
There's an evacuation advisory for the whole Shin-awara area.
新芦原全域に避難勧告が出てる
Are you travelers?
旅行者の人?
Do you understand what I—
言葉は…
I'm sorry.
すみません
I guess you do.
分かりますね
Yes.
はい　御厚意感謝します
Thank you for your consideration.
I apologize for the discourtesy,
but might I ask you a few questions like this?
無礼を承知でお願いしたいのですが
このままの体勢で　いくつか質問させていただいても
Go ahead.
どうぞ
What is this "evacuation advisory"?
避難勧告とは?
Tokyo has fallen to the Martians' attack.
火星人の襲撃で　東京が陥落したという話です
This town is no longer safe.
ここも危ない
We would like to contact the relevant authorities and inform them that we are safe.
私達は然るべき機関に赴き　自らの無事を伝えたいのです
Your embassy, I assume?
大使館ですか　この状況下で機能してるとは思えない
It's unlikely they'll still be staffed under the circumstances.
Since the assassination of the Vers princess yesterday, the United Earth—
昨日のヴァース王女暗殺事件以降　地球連合は…
Princess Asseylum...
アセイラム姫は…
is alive.
生きています
She did not take part in the parade.
彼女はパレードに参加していません
She was unwell from Earth's gravity,
慣れない地球の重力で体調を崩し
and a double took her place.
代わりの者が…
It must be hard on her.
心中お察し致します
First I've heard of that theory.
個性的な仮説だ
A transport should be here shortly.
もうすぐ輸送車が到着する
I texted Inko earlier.
さっき韻子にメールしておいたんだ
You're welcome to join me.
一緒に行こう
スレイン・トロイヤード
Slaine Troyard...
I cannot believe that you are to be my navigator.
貴様がこのトリルランの水先案内人とは
はっ　クルーテオ卿より仰せつかりました
I was ordered to by Count Cruhteo.
Whatever.
ふんっ　ならいい…
Just don't slow me down, Terran.
せめて足だけは引っ張ってくれるなよ　地球人
You're a lifesaver!
助かったよ　よりによってこんな時に車がガス欠なんて
That was the worst possible time to run out of gas.
Damn right you should appreciate it.
感謝してくださいよ　先生
That goes for you too, Inaho.
おめぇもだぜ　伊奈帆
Yeah.
Would you get off your ass?
お前も堂々とサボってんなよ
Anyway...
それにしても…
Are they Russian, maybe? Or Scandinavian?
ロシア…いや北欧か?
You don't see many of those in Shin-awara.
新芦原じゃ珍しいな
It's all good, right?
いいじゃんいいじゃん　美人は大歓迎だって
A chick's a chick.
And this one's a ten out of ten!
お手柄伊奈帆君　10ポイント
Thanks.
ありがとう
Guys...
男子…
KG-7　アレイオン
KG-7 Areion!
What are you people doing?
あなた達何やってるの　ここは避難完了してるはずでしょ
Shouldn't you have evacuated?
I know that voice!
その声…ユキさんですか
Is that you, Yuki?
Inko?
韻子ちゃん?　じゃもしかしてなお君も?
Wait, is Nao with you?
Are you kidding me?
もうどうして…
Hey, if the Cataphracts are on the move,
does that mean the enemy is coming here?
つか　カタフラクト隊が出動って　敵が来るんすか　この街に
That's right.
そうよ　東京から高熱源体が近付いてるの
We've got high-temperature readings closing in from Tokyo.
This area will be a battlefield soon.
このエリアも交戦想定区域よ　引き返して
Turn around!
But the ferry dock is this way!
でも　フェリー埠頭はここを抜けないと
Forget the dock!
とにかく　安全な場所を探して逃げて
Go and find a safe place!
We'll hold them off!
私達で食い止めるから
Inaho.
伊奈帆…
Yeah.
Enemy fighters at one o'clock.
1時の方向より　敵航空機編隊接近
Suicidal, are they?
わざわざ犬死にするために現れたか
Well, happy to oblige.
よろしい　まずは見せしめだ
But first, a warning.
Target merge. Commencing attack.
ターゲットマージ　これより攻撃に移る
全弾命中
All missiles, direct hit!
て…敵健在　無傷です
E-Enemy still intact!
It's undamaged!
Sky rats.
カス共が…
Slaine?
スレイン
Yes, sir.
はい
やれやれやれやれ　躾がなってないじゃないか　クルーテオ卿
Dear oh dear.
Count Crutheo didn't train you nearly enough.
Very well.
まあよい　ならばこのトリルランが教育しよう
Then I, Trillram, shall educate you
in the pleasures of war!
戦場の悦という物を
They've started, huh?
始まったか
Message from HQ!
本部より入電
Fighters have encountered an enemy aircraft.
航空部隊は敵飛行部隊と接触　現在交戦中
They're fighting as we speak!
What's wrong? The reception's quite poor.
何だ　電波状態が良くないな
It's radio jamming.
ジャミングだ　強力な妨害電波でこっちの指揮系統を混乱させる
They're using powerful electromagnetic waves to disrupt our chain of command.
Just like fifteen years ago.
15年前と同じ　奴らの手だ
It's one of their tricks.
Don't talk to me about the past, you fraud.
何が15年前だ…ペテン師め
Shit! He's right on my ass!
くそっ　ケツを取られた
We got you!
援護に向かう
What?!
何っ
There's no greater beauty than crushing someone who is fully aware they are about to die.
散り際をわきまえぬ者は美しくないぞ
Well, Slaine?
どうだスレイン
How does it feel to watch your former countrymen die pathetically from your safe little perch?
かつての同胞が無様に死んでいく様を高見から見下ろす気持ちは
All fighters have been destroyed.
航空部隊　全滅
Enemy aircraft is continuing on its path to Shin-awara.
敵飛行部隊は尚も新芦原市に接近中
Let's pick up the pace.
急ぐぞ
There's our ride.
迎えだ
Indeed.
Now, as agreed, we will return to our motherland of Vers and collect our knighthood.
これで我々は締約通り　騎士の称号と共に
母なる故郷　ヴァースへ凱旋するのだ
It's been a long, challenging mission, hasn't it, Rayet?
長らく苦労をかけたな　ライエ
Not at all, Father.
いいえ　お父様
We've reached our destination.
目的地上空
Good. Drop me.
よし　降ろせ
Yes, sir.
はい　ニロケラス　ディスコネクト
Nilokeras, disconnect.
Here it comes!
来るぞ
Hail, Lord Trillram! We were awaiting your arrival.
トリルラン卿　お待ち申し上げておりました
Yes, a thousand congratulations for completing your mission.
うむ　大役ご苦労であった
That's...
これが　アルドノアの輝き…
the light of Aldnoah!
Now farewell, noble rats.
いざさらばだ　ドブネズミの諸君
It would be most troublesome for you to go squeaking to the wrong people later on.
後々チューチューと余計な鳴き声を立てられても困るのでね
Huh?
Well, well.
おや…これは可愛らしいこネズミさんだ
What a darling little rat!
You're not getting away!
逃がさないぞ
Enemy Cataphract spotted!
敵カタフラクトを捕捉
The bastard's chasing down a civilian!
野郎　民間人を襲っています
Move to attack. We'll finish him off quickly.
攻撃開始だ　一気に決着を付けて
Keep laser comms up. Do not break formation.
レーザー通信を併用　連携を乱すな
But—
しかし…
I said attack!
攻撃開始だ
Fire!
撃て
Stop! Helping the girl comes first!
よせ　民間人の保護が先だ
What the hell? We're not harming it.
何だ?　弾丸が…
Warrant Officer Kaizuka, grab the girl! I'll cover you!
界塚准尉　生き残りを保護しろ
カバーをする
Roger!
了解
鞠戸大尉　私の隊だ
Lieutenant Marito, this is my platoon!
You don't give the orders here!
勝手な指示を出すな
What do they think they're doing?
何のつもりだ
Keep going!
行け
Get on!
乗って
Civilian secured!
民間人確保
Fire grenades!
グレネード
I said, you don't give the orders here!
命令するなと言っている
What the hell's with that freak's body?
一体何なんです　あいつの体は
Don't let it get to you!
怯むな
Fire at will!
撃ちまくれ
What on Earth?
何なの…
That's the trash taken care of.
邪魔者は片付けた
Now, what say we finish this game of cat and rat?
ネズミ退治の続きをしようか
逃げろ　界塚
Get out of here, Kaizuka!
Lieutenant Marito!
鞠戸大尉
A rat's death or a wounded lion's death, huh?
臆病に死ぬか　蛮勇に死すか
You think you're choosing to make a noble sacrifice?
誇り高い選択をしているつもりかも
Too bad.
残念…
Lieutenant Marito!
鞠戸大尉
HQ, please respond!
司令本部　応答願います　司令本部
HQ!
Haven't we been going in circles this whole time?
さっきから同じとこぐるぐる回ってませんか
What else am I supposed to do?
どうしろってんだ
This is Warrant Officer Kaizuka. Do you read?
こちら　界塚ユキ准尉　聞こえる?
Yuki?
ユキさん?
Take this girl and get out of here!
その子を乗せて　そのまま走って
Warrant Officer Kaizuka, what's—
界塚准尉　一体何が…
Just hurry!
急いで
Sergeant!
軍曹
大人
Old man!
手こずらせるな　ネズミ
Quit making this so difficult, rats!
Inko! Step on it!
韻子　もっとスピードを
I'm trying!
やってる
He's catching up!
このままじゃ追いつかれる
We're too heavy, okay?!
重すぎるんだって
Brake.
ブレーキ
Brake hard.
ブレーキ踏んで
Uh, what?
何って?
Do it now.
早く
Brake!
ブレーキ
Now accelerate!
アクセル
Right!
はい
Pesky critters!
ちょこまかと
Okojo!
オコジョ
We gotta save Yuki!
ユキさん助けねぇと
You're out of your mind, man!
危ねぇって
Sorry!
ごめん
It's all good!
大丈夫
We're totally gonna make it!
このまま逃げ切りだ
Inaho!
伊奈帆
Oh?
Inaho!
伊奈帆…
Let me help you with that.
手伝ってやろうか
Okisuke...
起助…
I toyed with them too long.
遊びすぎたか
Nice job!
よくやった
It's okay, you guys!
もう大丈夫だ　二人共
We aren't being followed anymore—
あいつはもう追ってこない
Hey, Inaho.
なあ　伊奈帆　オコジョは?
Where's Okojo?
No way.
嘘だろう
Warrant Officer Kaizuka, this is Marito.
界塚准尉　こちら鞠戸　聞こえるか
Do you copy?
Instructor Marito.
鞠戸　教官…
Kaizuka!
界塚
Listen. That Martian is after you guys.
聞け　火星人はお前を追っている
He still hasn't attacked the ferry dock.
フェリー埠頭への攻撃はまだ無い
Try and draw him away, but no crazy stuff.
できるだけ奴を引き付ける　だが無茶はするな
Don't die on me.
必ず生きて還れ
Inaho?
伊奈帆?
Apparently our pursuer is persistent.
さっきの奴　まだ僕らを追ってきてるって
But we might be able to use that to buy time for the ferry full of refugees to ship out.
でも　その隙に避難民を乗せたフェリーが出港できるかも
If we act as bait.
僕らが囮になれば
What the hell are you talking about?
おい　何言ってんだ
We can reach the school from here by using the utility tunnels.
共同溝を使えばここから学校まで行ける
So damn what?
だから何だよ
The school hangars have training units in them.
格納庫に行けば練習機がある
And real ammunition from our live-fire training.
夏季演習の時の弾薬も
Dude...
お前…
Let's fight.
戦おう　ユキ姉達の代わりに　今度は僕らが
We have to pick up where my sister and her squad left off.
Let's fight that Martian Cataphract.
あの火星カタフラクトと
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:つっちー   翻译:mam&低音子   校对:小可&zwx   时间轴:亢奋の蛇   压制:河蟹
rei
Zero
0　始まりにも　終わりにも　変わる光
hajimari ni mo
Both the beginning
owari ni mo
and the end
kawaru hikari
see the changing of light
shita ni muketa mama
Back when I decided
下に向けたまま　かざすのを止めた　あの時
kazasu no wo yameta ano toki
that I would stop fooling myself and others,
LP no saizu no awanai uso bakari narabete
all I did was pile lie upon lie,
ALD noah
サイズの合わない　嘘ばかり並べて
miushinai mizukara subete ni tsumazuita
with no chance to be comfortable with myself
見失い　自ら全てに　つまずいた
earth terasu a to a
Shine on Earth
AS　照らす　影と栄
kurikaesu count
Count again
繰り返すcount　明日の零時のサイン
asu no reiji no sign
The sign of twelve in the morning
lie mo die
Lie and die
LIVE or DIE
mienai hikari no sen
Under the sunlight,
見えない　光の線
ochiru dake de
just from that,
文字だけで　生kill-場所捨てて
kuruu basho subete
everything goes mad
namae mo nai soko ni
Even though I vainly seek answers
名前も居ない　そこに　答えを求めてても
kotae wo motometetemo
from that kind of nameless place,
kaze ni tokashita inochi no rei
I won't throw away my soul
風にとかした　命のRain　投げ捨てない
nagesutenai
as it is carried on the wind
kakedashi no namida
These are my first tears
駆け出しのナミダ
kitai mo yami no owari mo iranai
I don't need expectations or an end to the darkness
期待も闇も終わりもいらない
zero ni nareba
When all goes back to zero,
ゼロになれば　裸足のphrase-1
hadashi no brave one
I walk barefoot, and with courage